Charles B. Dulcan Collection 078
People's Archive, MLK Library
Charles B. Dulcan Collection
1912-1952
People's Archive, MLK Library
078
52.5 Linear feet
27 Boxes
Biographical / Historical
Born in Winnipeg, Canada in 1888, Charles B. Dulcan, Sr. was a longtime Hecht Company executive. As a child, he moved with his family to Baltimore, Maryland. When he relocated to Washington, D.C. years later, one of his first jobs was as a part-time employee at the Hecht Company. Throughout the 41 years he was with the company, Dulcan was promoted several times, serving as Vice President, General Merchandising Manager, and finally as the Managing Director of all stores in the D.C. metropolitan area. Dulcan was active in the Metropolitan Police Boys' Club, Community Chest, the American Cancer Society, and the Washington Chapter of the American Red Cross, among many other civic and local organizations. He and his wife, Elizabeth, had three sons, Edward, Alvin, and Charles, Jr. On January 6, 1957 Dulcan died of a heart attack at Doctors Hospital.
Custodial History
Ronald Dulcan donated this collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains clippings, photographs, correspondence, organizational information, and 78 RPM records related to Charles B. Dulcan and the Hecht Company.
Custodial History
Ronald Dulcan donated this collection to the DC Public Library.
Arrangement
Series 1: Scrapbooks (1912-1952, undated) This series consists of scrapbooks containing photographs and clippings. Clippings cover subjects such as the Hecht Company's advertising, publicity, and merchandising. Series 2: Correspondence (1952) This series contains correspondence to Charles B. Dulcan, Sr. regarding his 1952 promotion to the position of Managing Director of Hecht stores in the D.C. Metropolitan area. Series 3: Organization information (1926-1951) This series includes annual statements and a history of Hecht Baltimore Properties. Series 4: Records (1947-1951, undated) This series contains recordings of classical music, interviews with Charles B. Dulcan, Sr., and radio programs about the Hecht Company.
Music; Radio programs; Ephemera; Scrapbooks; Department stores; Correspondence; Organizational Records
- Series 1: Scrapbooks
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of scrapbooks containing photographs and clippings. Subjects of the clippings include Hecht's advertising, publicity, and merchandising.
  - Untitled, 1912-1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1924-1925 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1926-1929 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1930-1933 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1930-1933 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1937-1938 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 50th Birthday Scrapbook, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1938-1939 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1940-1941 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1941-1943 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1943-1945 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1944-1946 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1948-1949 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1949-1951 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Brand Names Award, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1951-1952 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, 1951-1952 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - "Who Wants Seven Lean Years", Undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - "Good Wishes and Good Luck from all your 3460 Associates", Undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Photo Scrapbook, Undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Loose images, Undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Cosmopolitan Club Award, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Photos - Arlington Opening, Undated (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Series 2: Correspondence
  This series contains correspondence to C.B. Dulcan regarding his 1952 promotion to the position of Managing Director of Hecht stores in the DC Metropolitan area.
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Series 3: Organization Information
  This series includes Annual Statements and a History of Hecht Baltimore Properties.
  - Annual Statements, 1926-1933 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Annual Statements, 1934-1940 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Annual Statements, 1940-1946 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Annual Statements, 1946-1951 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - History of Hecht Baltimore Properties, 1948 (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Series 4: Records
  This series consists of recordings of classical music, interviews with C.B. Dulcan, and radio programs about the Hecht Company.
  - Ravel, Bolero, Undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Beethoven, Sonata in C Sharp Minor, Undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - C.B. Dulcan Interview - U.S. Department of State, Undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Hecht Co. "Community Reporter" Broadcast of arrival of Santa Claus at B and O, 11/3/1951 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - WRC Honor Roll - The Hecht Co., Undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - C.B. Dulcan - Introductory Speech Training Class, Undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Hecht Co. Dedicatory Program, 11/1/1947 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Woman's World, 10/31/1947 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Cosmopolitan Club Awards, 4/24/1952 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Hecht Co. Opening, 11/1/1947 (Box 27, Folder 5)